They've kidnapped Osgood
and they've stolen the location
of every Zygon on Earth.
- 'Doctor, the ceasefire's broken down.'
- Call me now.
They turned into monsters
and they came for us.
We couldn't fight 'em.
You can't tell who's who.
Oh, come on. These are eggs
or pods or whatever. Look!
God, that's me.
But I don't see how these ARE duplicates.
That's not how Zygons work.
- These... ARE the humans!
- Please!
Kill the traitors.
There isn't any backup, is there?
UNIT neutralised in the UK.
More or less.
I'm sorry, but Clara's dead.
Clara... Clara!
You're breaking up!
'The invasion has happened. You're
probably surrounded by Zygons.
'Get to the TARDIS,
'get yourself safe.
'Apparently my plane
is never going to land.
'Let's see what we can do about that!'
'I'm sorry, but Clara's dead.'
Dream checks...
Dream checks, dream checks...
'It's your decision, Doctor.
'Truth or consequences.'
Doctor...
Missed!
I know what you are.
Please... Please.
I'm going to set you free.
Humans cannot accept
the way we really are.
If we cannot hide, we must fight.
You are going to be the first.
The first to make the humans see.
Help me.
Help me...
Help! Help me...
Commander here. The first
one has been changed.
I'm going to UNIT to
retrieve the Osgood box.
Doctor?
Doctor!
Any questions?
Why do you have a Union Jack parachute?
- Camouflage.
- Camouflage?
Yes, we're in Britain.
Ooh, your specs are broken.
I'll fix 'em. You can
wear mine, they're sonic.
- Sonic specs?
- Yeah!
Isn't that a bit pointless?
Like a visual hearing aid?
What's wrong with pointless?
I once invented an invisible watch.
Spot the design flaw.
You're talking nonsense to distract
me from being really scared.
It's one of your known character traits.
Don't look at my browser history.
Whoa!
Yeah, I said "don't".
Why didn't that Zygon blow
us up with her big bazooka?
She did blow us up with her big bazooka.
This is us being blown
up with a big bazooka.
But she seems to know what she's doing.
The first thing I'D do if I
wanted to invade the world
- would be to kill you.
- Thanks.
I wouldn't even let you get
talking, like you always do.
- Bullet between the eyes, first thing.
- Again, thank you.
- 12 times, if necessary.
- Ah, yes. Why limit yourself?
You've really thought
this through, haven't you?
I'm a big fan.
But she gave you a chance
to get out. She hesitated.
If she had Clara's memory print,
she'd know better than
to give you even a second.
You've gone quiet because
I mentioned Clara.
You think she might be dead.
Yes.
Are you OK?
I don't know. I'm still in the hope phase.
- How's that going?
- Hell.
Please talk about something else.
Why do they want to destroy the ceasefire?
Don't think of them as rational.
They're different. They don't
care about human beings,
they don't care about their own people.
They think the rest of
Zygonkind are traitors.
It's a splinter group.
Clara.
Well, not Clara. The Zygon who...
The Zygon who probably
killed her. Read it.
- It says, "I'm awake."
- What does she mean?
A political awakening?
Why would she be sending me propaganda?
She just blew me up with a big bazooka.
Never really met Clara.
Pretty strong, yeah?
She was amazing.
No.
Not was. Is.
It's not from the Zygon. It's from Clara.
How?
She's not dead, she's in a pod somewhere.
They need a live feed to the
information in her brain.
But she's fighting back.
- She's trying to take control,
piece by piece. - Texting?
How much more human do you get?
The Zygon probably doesn't
even know it sent this,
or why it misfired that bazooka.
You don't know. It's just a theory.
Yes, it's just a theory.
But how's the hope phase now?
- Worse than ever.
- Then we've got a game!
Hello. If you're watching this, I
have been captured and interrogated.
During the interrogation,
I have revealed to you
the existence of the Osgood box.
I have revealed its location and
the combination to open this safe.
And guess what?
I lied.
The Osgood box exists.
But it's not here. Stop
looking. Really, stop.
The Osgood box can end the ceasefire.
The Osgood box can start the war.
The Osgood box can wipe out all humankind.
But there's a reason it's
called the Osgood box.
Haven't you guessed?
Hello! Hi!
Hello.
Dr John Disco.
It was my plane.
I had a big plane
for purposes of poncing about.
It went off with a massive bang
about half a mile that way?
Actually...
- It's fine. We're... we're
fine, aren't we? - Yeah. Yeah.
Yes, yes, we're fine.
Just, um, move along.
(Come on.)
She's answered.
- Hello!
- You're dead.
Yes, well, I'm dead now,
and I think I might be a
bit more dead in a minute.
What's your plan, Zygella?
I don't have a plan.
Come on, you don't invade planets
without having kind of plan.
That's why they're called "planets"
to remind you to PLAN IT?
Hey-hey! That's good!
Pun-tastic. Dr Pun-tastic!
Oh, come on, that was a good one, Zygella!
Don't call me Zygella.
My name's Bonnie.
And you're winking at me.
I am not winking at you.
Where is the Osgood box?
You do know what winking means?
You're sending out some
very mixed messages here.
You know I'm over 2,000 years old?
I'm old enough to be your Messiah.
'I am not winking at
you. Where is the box?!'
We need some wheels. The van!
OK. Non-verbal communication.
I assume that you never
bothered to learn Morse code...
(Specs! Setting 137.)
Tell me!
OK, we'll have to try
something else. 20 questions.
Where's your pod?
Is it in a tunnel?
Is it in London?
Thanks very much. Gotcha!
'Stay where you are, Clara.'
We're coming to get you.
And for God's sake, don't
let her into your memories!
Memories? What memories? What has she got?
Don't tell her where the Osgood box is,
and above all, don't tell her WHAT it is.
- Obviously, the Zygon could
hear that. - Obviously.
So she's going to poke around inside
Clara's mind, looking for answers.
The mind of Clara Oswald. She
may never find her way out!
I don't think I've ever
seen you smile before.
Dazzling, isn't it?
Oh! I got a ping on Clara's phone.
It's the location Bonnie
sent the text from.
A shopping centre, south London.
Ah, London! Perpetual city,
cradle of culture, here we come!
Clara, stay safe.
She's posted a video link.
'A video supposedly showing
an alien in south London
'is posted across the internet...'
This is the same place Bonnie
texted from. We need to hurry.
Hello.
Oh, there's no point turning over.
There's nothing better on the other side.
I could erase your mind.
Then why haven't you?
Having trouble?
Let's see what I can do.
See, this thing... works
two ways, you know.
I want those memories! Trouble
is, you're asking me for them,
which means you can't access them, right?
I can make you tell me.
No, you can't, otherwise
you would have done already.
I can kill you.
- Go on, then.
- You think you're calling my bluff.
I AM calling your bluff.
You need me alive.
Only as a source of information.
- Then you'd better start asking questions.
- You'd better not lie.
You see, that's your problem.
I am a brilliant liar. How
are you ever going to know?
Oh, Clara.
For a moment, I thought you were clever.
Our hearts are linked. Beat for beat.
The one thing you and I can never do
is lie to each other.
Oh, that scared you, didn't it?
London!
What a dump.
- London's OK.
- No, it's not, it's a dump.
You spend an awful lot of time
here, considering it's a dump.
I spend an awful lot of time
being kidnapped, tortured,
shot at and exterminated.
Doesn't mean I like it.
Well... This is where the video was shot.
Bonnie was here.
Come on, Doctor.
There's electricity in the air.
It stinks. It smells like... barbecues.
Oh...
Now, listen to me. Here's
what we're going to do.
I'm going to ask you questions
and if you don't tell me the
exact and complete truth,
I will know and I WILL kill
you. Do you understand me?
Yes.
I will slaughter you
in that pod right now.
Am I lying to you?
- No.
- Good. Then we'll begin.
Where is the Osgood box?
You will answer me, Clara.
Truth or consequences, lie
and you die. Where is it?
UNIT HQ. Under the Tower of London.
- Where, specifically? - The
Black Archive. - Ah, yes.
The dark little storage facility
for forbidden alien tech,
where this all began.
Who has access to it?
The Osgoods.
Only the Osgoods?
The Doctor sealed it
up after the last time.
Didn't want UNIT interfering
with the ceasefire.
Don't avoid the question. Do
only the Osgoods have access?
The Doctor has access, too.
Who else?
Ah. You.
YOU have access?
Yes.
Is it a key? Or a code?
No, a pass. A key code?
Give it to me now.
I can't.
Interesting. You're not lying.
- No, I'm not. - But you have
access of some kind. - Obviously.
- Give it to me now.
- I told you. I can't.
You KNOW I'm not lying,
I can't give you access.
OK, how do you get in there?
How, physically, do you get in?
- It's automatic.
- But how? Tell me!
The door is keyed to my body print.
Ah, yes, your body print.
You can't give me access,
because I have access already.
- I'm you.
- Yes.
And what am I going to find?
What's in the Osgood box?
Clara?
The box ends the ceasefire.
So I'm told. How?
There's a button inside the box.
Press it, it will transmit a signal
that will unmask every Zygon
on the planet for up to an hour.
What's there to smile about?
Mass panic followed by a war.
Every Zygon on our side at a stroke.
20 million Zygons against
seven billion humans...
That's not a war you can win.
Then we will die in the fire,
instead of living in chains.
Most of your own kind don't want that.
Then it's time we stopped
giving them a choice.
It's time you asked the
most important question.
- Which is?
- I'm waiting.
Why's it called an Osgood box?
- I'm not telling you.
- Good.
I've been looking forward
to hearing you scream.
I'm not telling you, because when
you get to the Black Archive,
you'll find out for
yourself, and when you do,
you're going to want to speak to me again.
Am I lying to you?
See you later.
What's your name?
Osgood.
No, no, no. Your first name?
What's YOUR first name?
Basil.
Petronella.
Let's just stick with what we had.
I need to ask you...
...because it's important,
because it might matter...
What's important?
Which one are you? Human or Zygon?
Whoever you are, we can help you.
It wasn't me.
They attacked me.
They saw me. I had to...
It's OK, it's OK, it's
OK. It's OK, it's OK.
A commander came. She turned me back!
We can help. We can help you.
- Doctor, we can help him, can't we?
- I'm not sure.
Please!
Come back! Come back!
North America reporting
back to High Command.
I'm going to the Black Archive.
- I'll open it up, you will follow.
- Of course.
But first, locate the Doctor.
If possible, duplicate him,
and then kill him.
It will be my pleasure.
I can't help you just now, but...
Why?
- I was happy like this. I was
happy here. - I understand.
I can't change. I can't hide.
Let us help you.
No!
You're truth or consequences.
We're not. We're really not.
I'm not part of your fight.
I never wanted to fight anyone,
I just wanted to live here.
Why can't I just live?
We're on your side.
I'm not on anyone's side.
This is my home.
Listen, we are not them.
I can't go back now.
You've taken my life!
No, no, no! Stop! Stop! Stop!
They will kill me.
There it is, Osgood. There's their plan.
Unmask everyone, provoke fear,
paranoia, provoke a war.
- Doctor...
- Kate! Are you all right?
- Of course I am. Why wouldn't I be?
- It's just I'd heard otherwise.
I'm fine. Doctor, we know where
the Zygon command centre is.
We know where Clara's pod
is. We can take you there.
Well, how very convenient,
because that's just exactly
what we're looking for.
And here it is, the Black Archive.
Oh, I do like being you, Clara.
Everyone just waves you on past.
Now, how does this work?
Well, they like a good cave, don't they?
How many of these pods are occupied?
We don't know.
Which one is Clara's?
Well, that's strange. It was here before.
Doctor...
I think they're Zygons.
Oh, you tricky little monkeys!
Normalise.
Well, Clara, I think you're
reaching the end of your...
The Doctor is here.
'Don't kill him. We need him alive.'
What for?
Because I just found out why
it's called an Osgood box.
- There's two of them.
- Two Osgoods, two boxes.
Operation Double. What did you expect?
What's in them, Doctor? Tell me. Now!
One box normalises all the Zygons.
- And the other?
- Destroys them.
Which is which?
That would be telling!
Which box normalises the Zygons, Doctor?
Tell me, or she dies.
No. This is war. You pull the
trigger, you pay the price.
Kill her.
The blue one!
The blue one! The blue one
normalises all your people.
Are you lying? Are you
lying to me, Doctor?
No, I'm not.
And when you open up the box,
you'll see I'm not lying.
Doctor?
Doctor!
Yeah, I know.
Bring him to me!
- Sorry, Doctor! Self-defence.
- You're you!
- I'm me.
- How did you survive?
Five rounds' rapid.
I'm sorry, Doctor, I
know you don't approve.
Why does peacekeeping
always involve killing?
Is this the lot?
No, there are plenty more of them.
They were the nearest.
You are you? I'm me.
But human or Zygon?
Me.
What are we dealing with?
20 million Zygons about to be unmasked.
You don't know whether
they are human or not.
And you can't fight
them, not with soldiers.
Which leads me to a very big question.
I was really hoping that it wouldn't.
The Z-67, Sullivan's gas, the
gas that kills the Zygons.
- So you took it. - Well, you
know how it is. Daddy knows best.
That's what's in the red box, yes?
Of course it is.
If I remember rightly,
it causes a chain reaction
in the atmosphere, turns every
Zygon on Earth inside-out.
Let me negotiate peace. You
can't commit mass murder...
Then why did you leave the gas with us?
The boxes are safeguards for both species.
- You agreed to that.
- I never agreed to that.
Yes, you did, then I wiped your memory.
You agreed to that, too. But
that's why there were two Osgoods
to police the ceasefire.
One human and one Zygon,
to keep the secrets and keep the peace.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
Truly. But the peace is failing already.
Come on.
It's no good, Bonnie, you can't win.
I don't care.
Hi! Hello! Hello! Oh, hello!
Hi. Hi. Stop this. Stop this, please.
Let me take both of these boxes away.
We'll forgive, we'll forget.
And the ceasefire will stand.
No.
Doctor, which of these buttons do I press?
Doctor, which one? Truth or consequences?
Truth or consequences?
This is the moment we've
all been waiting for.
Make-your-mind-up time!
One of those buttons
will destroy the Zygons,
release the imbecile's gas.
The other one detonates the nuclear
warhead under the Black Archive.
It'll destroy everyone in London.
Bonnie. Bonnie, sweetheart!
One of those buttons will
unmask every Zygon in the world.
The other one cancels their
ability to change form.
It'll make them human beings for ever.
There are safeguards beyond safeguards.
I did this on a very important day for me
- and this ceasefire WILL stand.
- This is wrong.
No, it's not.
You are responsible for all the
violence. All of the suffering.
- No, I'm not. - Yes. - No.
Yes, you engineered this situation,
Doctor. This is your fault.
No, it's not, it's your fault.
I had to do what I've done.
- So did I.
- We have been treated like cattle.
- So, what? - We've been
left to fend for ourselves.
- So is everyone. - It's not
fair. - Oh, it's not fair!
Oh, I didn't realise that it
was not fair! You know what?
My TARDIS doesn't work properly
and I don't have my own personal tailor.
The things don't equate.
These things have happened,
Zygella, they are facts.
YOU just want cruelty to beget cruelty.
You're not superior to
people who were cruel to you,
you're just a whole bunch
of new cruel people.
A whole bunch of new cruel people
being cruel to some other people,
who'll end up being cruel to you.
The only way anyone can live in peace
is if they're prepared to forgive.
Why don't you break the cycle?
Why should we?
What is it that you actually want?
- War.
- Ah, ah right!
And when this war is over,
when you have a homeland free from humans,
what do you think it's going to be like?
Do you know? Have you thought about it?
Have you given it any consideration?
Because you're very close
to getting what you want.
What's it going to be
like? Paint me a picture.
Are you going to live in houses?
Do you want people to go to work?
Will there be holidays?
Oh! Will there be music?
Do you think people will
be allowed to play violins?
Who's going to make the violins?
Well? Oh, you don't actually know, do you?
Because, like every other
tantrumming child in history,
Bonnie, you don't actually
know what you want.
So, let me ask you a question about
this brave new world of yours.
When you've killed all the bad
guys, and when it's all perfect
and just and fair, when
you have finally got it
exactly the way you want it,
what are you going to do
with the people like you?
The troublemakers.
How are you going to protect
your glorious revolution
from the next one?
We'll win.
Oh, will you? Well,
maybe... maybe you WILL win!
But nobody wins for long.
The wheel just keeps turning.
So, come on.
Break the cycle.
Why are you still talking?
Because I want to get you to
see, and I'm almost there!
You know what I see, Doctor?
A box.
A box with everything I need.
A 50% chance.
For us, too.
And we're off! Fingers on
buzzers! Are you feeling lucky?
Are you ready to play the game?
Who's going to be quickest?
- Who's going to be luckiest?
- This is not a game!
No, it's not a game, sweetheart,
and I mean that most sincerely.
Why are you doing this?
Yes, I'd quite like to know that,
too. You set this up... why?
Because it's not a game, Kate.
This is a scale model of war.
Every war ever fought, right
there in front of you.
Because it's always the same.
When you fire that first shot,
no matter how right you feel,
you have no idea who's going to die!
You don't know whose children
are going to scream and burn!
How many hearts will be broken!
How many lives shattered!
How much blood will spill
until everybody does until
what they were always going to have
to do from the very beginning...
Sit down and talk!
Listen to me. Listen, I just...
I just want you to think.
Do you know what thinking is?
It's a fancy word for changing your mind.
I will not change my mind.
Then you will die stupid.
Alternatively, you could
step away from that box,
you can walk right out of that door
and you could stand your revolution down.
No!
I'm not stopping this, Doctor. I
started it. I will not stop it.
You think they'll let me
go, after what I've done?
You're all the same, you screaming kids.
You know that?
"Look at me, I'm unforgiveable."
Well, here's the
unforeseeable. I forgive you...
after all you've done.
I forgive you.
You don't understand.
You will never understand.
I don't understand?
Are you kidding? Me?
Of course I understand.
You mean, you call this a
war? This funny little thing?
This is not a war!
I fought in a bigger war
than you will ever know.
I did worse things than
you could ever imagine.
And when I close my eyes...
...I hear more screams than anyone
could ever be able to count!
And do you know what you
do with all that pain?
Shall I tell you where you put it?
You hold it tight...
...till it burns your hand,
and you say this...
No-one else will ever
have to live like this!
No-one else will have to feel this pain!
Not on my watch!
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I know.
I know, thank you.
Well?
It's empty, isn't it?
Both boxes. There's nothing in them...
just buttons.
Of course.
Do you know how you know that?
Because you've started to think like me.
It's hell, isn't it?
No-one should have to think like that.
And no-one will.
Not on our watch.
Gotcha!
How can you be so sure?
Because you have a disadvantage, Zygella.
I know that face.
This is all very well, but we
know the boxes are empty now.
We can't forget that.
No. Well, um, you've said
that the last 15 times.
You didn't wipe my memory.
No. Just Kate's. Oh, and your
little friend's here, of course.
When they wake up, they won't
remember what you've done.
It'll be our secret.
- You're going to protect me?
- You're one of us now,
whether you like it, or not.
I don't understand how
you could just forgive me.
Because I've been where you have.
There was another box.
I was going to press another button.
I was going to wipe out
all of my own kind...
Man, woman and child... I
was so sure I was right.
What happened?
The same thing that happened to you.
I let Clara Oswald get inside my head.
Trust me.
She doesn't leave.
Zygon High Command, the
ceasefire is back in place.
The rebels are standing
down. You are all...
...safe.
- The TARDIS.
What does it stand for?
What?
You're kidding me?
Surely you know that?
I've heard a couple of different versions.
I made it up from the initials.
It stands for "Totally And
Radically Driving In Space".
Do you want to come?
All of the future, all of history,
and all of the universe?
More than anything.
But I think I have to stay.
I've got a couple of
boxes to keep an eye on.
And a world to keep safe.
Fair enough.
Clara, would you mind, um...
Mind what?
I'll see you in the TARDIS, OK?
Uh... yeah, sure.
Take care, you!
You take care of him. Don't
let him die, or anything.
What if he's really annoying?
Then, fine. Got ya.
I need to know... which one are you?
I'm Osgood.
Human or Zygon?
I'll answer that question one day.
Do you know when day that will be?
The day nobody cares about the answer.
Gotcha!
Oh, look at his face.
It's almost not fair.
I don't... I don't... How... how...
Oh, think it through, Doctor.
It wouldn't be right, would it?
To carry on using Clara's face...
When there's a vacancy.
- Zygella?
- Osgood!
But which one of you...
Osgood!
It doesn't matter which of us is which.
All that matters is that Osgood lives.
And nothing's going to stop us!
You're a credit to your
species, Petronella Osgood.
No, Basil.
We're a credit to both of them.
Oh, and you should know...
I'm a very big fan.
- So, you must have thought I
was dead for a while? - Yeah.
How was that?
Longest month of my life.
It could only have been five minutes!
I'll be the judge of time.
Ice creams?
Yes, ice creams.
Then back to work!
- What's today?
- Oh, you know, same old, same old.
Defending the Earth.
You must not watch this.
You can never unsee it.
24 hours ago, this station fell silent.
We've come to find out why.
- What are these?
- Morpheus. - What is Morpheus?
The Morpheus machine concentrates
the whole nocturnal experience.
- Now you can go a whole month
without sleep. - Time is money.
Congratulations, Professor.
You've conquered nature.
You've also created an abomination.
Run! Run! Run!
You can't stop them. None of us can.